foreign
I've been following the practice of no
theft which involves voluntary refraining from
which involves voluntary refraining from
pornography and masturbation
however this path has brought me to seek
your guidance because I've grown wary of
mere abstinence
my goal is to find true Liberation from
the internal sexual pressure
despite experiencing increased Vitality
through this practice no no fat
I still feel the weight of this pressure
Within Me
I request your assistance in finding the
genuine Freedom hmm
yeah so the next step is to um
to start Discerning the the mental
aspects of sensuality and Central craving
of sensuality and Central craving
so being celibate withdrawn from
sensuality not exposing yourself to
unsuitable sites and so on
um that's obviously necessary
and now you can start seeing uh
um the the mental counterparts of those
desires the main aspect being as we
already spoke about in those early
videos that no one wants in charity and
so on it's like um they're unpleasant
those pressures are unpleasant
they hurt
so what is your attitude towards pain
now having contained your craving for
having contained your craving for
pleasures
sexuality and so on having having
um having a practice sense restraint
withdrawal uh
uh
do you now have a version towards things
do you cultivate that aversion are you
resisting the discomfort of your body
of your unsatisfied body unsatisfied in
the old ways
because basically it's like taming the
central itch and the only way you used
to know how to tame it is to scratching
it so it's going to take a while
before the Mind stops associating each
with a scratch
but that can happen if you stick to it
if you if you abstain from scratching
by looking by physical behavior and so
on then abstain from scratching by
mentally indulging those thoughts
uh the nature of data will become more
apparent which is that it's unpleasant
and it's actually itches less if it's
left alone on the level of the Mind
that's where each is actually recruited
if you engage with it mentally
it translates into physical need
but it starts and remains fully rooted
in that in the uh in the on the mental
level so if you have been withdrawn not not
so if you have been withdrawn not not
delighting in it mentally not obviously
acting out physically
you could start seeing that edge for
what it is
it's slightly uncomfortable
but only from the point of view of
wanting to scratch it
and you learn how to become peaceful
within it
you learn how to come within the itch
and the need for scratching it
disappears because you realize that is
the more instantaneous way
of freeing yourself from the itch
come within the itch removes the itch
removes the pressure
scratching the itch relieves it on the
surface makes it worse on the inside so
it increases it next time and next time
and next time
but actually if you remain unmovable
internally in the heart of that edge it doesn't
in the heart of that edge it doesn't
itch
and in order to Aid that well there's
lots of other talks we did I mean I
can't possibly go through all of it now
but yes so contemplate again
the repulsiveness of things you are
attracted to the factual repulsiveness
don't contemplate them through the itch
and through trying to get rid of the
itch but when you're not itching then
bring those things to mind of the uh
uh repulsive nature that pertain to your
sexual desires and so on because bodies
are generally repulsive it's just the
Mind selectively only uh focus and pick
the signs of the of the agreeable shapes
and forms and so on ignoring the
disagreeable simultaneously there in in
it when the itch is present you mustn't
be doing all of this in order to get rid
of that sexual itch
because that's going to become another
way of trying to scratch ditch
so so another way of trying to scratch
the itch instead of acting out of it
through your normal behavior of
masturbation other sexual activities
other sexual activities
and I think with people with
that have done there's no fat some can't
start hating
hating
the objects that they sure they're
blaming the objects blaming the objects
for yeah hating women or hating the
other uh the thing that they sexually
attracted to hating sensuality hating
hating the world
so you just sort of yeah well that's
that's yourself you can't help if that
happens like mind might go that way you just you
like mind might go that way you just you
can't help not acting out of it so if
you are building a version towards these
things well that's fine in a way it will
subside if you don't act out of it so
don't be expressing that aversion don't
be sort of uh trying to like act by Body
by speech by mind hating revolving
around the hate because that's not where
the problem was rooted to begin with it
was rooted in you yourself not being
developed in regard to the itch of your
own body
when experienced you needed to scratch
it you are seeking means of scratching
it you were finding developing different
tastes of scratching it
all rooted in wanting to get rid of it
so you have to stop trying to get rid of
it which obviously they that person did
to physical restraint through uh
non-masturbation celibacy and so on and
now mentally the weight of that itch is
becoming apparent
so now you have to mentally not allow
your thoughts to sort of uh proliferate
and fantasies about these things but at
the same time you don't want to be
trying to get rid of the itch
because the itch is the reference point
for your development
if the itch is obscured
you don't know if you're if you're going
to move by it or not
so you don't need to seek the itch as
it's becoming obvious it's by not
seeking the scratching each becomes
apparent because you know sometimes people think
because you know sometimes people think
oh I need to go and expose myself to
sensuality to see if I'm free well if
you if you don't know if you're free
means you're not free if you're not free
from doubt in regard to sensuality means
you are still Within centrality
on the contrary you want to expose
yourself to date of sensuality you need
to say no to the means of scratching it
so sensory strength and virtue reveals
the sensual itch and if you think I
don't feel an itch increase the sense
restraint say no to more things seeing
with your eyes or hearing of the
pleasant kind and so on and then if
there's truly no pressure of the age
manifested you're free and you wouldn't
be going back to it because it was
always unpleasant to begin with would
you be scratching your wound once it's
healed and stopped itching it would be
stupid thing to do so also what I think
the person was asking might be uh
or is he expecting the itch to Disappear
Completely yes there's a pressure yeah
yeah yeah yeah so basically the the
pressure as I said it's pressured by the
need to scratch pressure pressures you
on account of your you're assumed
value of scratching
and that needs to change
you need to recognize that
it should never and it's never and it's
dangerous to scratch it basically
it's a decline it's a distraction it's
undoing scratching it and never scratch
it basically that in and of itself would
train your mind to get used to the
pressure and when the Mind stops
expecting the scratch
each will disappear you have to not
scratch the edge and you have to uh not
try to get rid of it
because that becomes another way of
trying to scratch it remove it yeah
so don't go towards it but don't deny it
but recognize the pressure is the
measure of what you need to get used to
it so imagine this pressure is
pressuring me now acutely let me live
with it and never act out of it
and let's see what happens
well what will happen is it will stop
pressuring it because I said the
acuteness of the pressure is because of
you still looking past it towards the
scratch of one kind or the other
Desiring pleasure lasting well exactly
yeah that in and of itself
perpetuates the the underlying desire I
mean aversion towards it yeah so if
you're a versatility you want it to go
away to never be there that's already your
to never be there that's already your
basically same on the same level as
desire to scratch it so
which is good to begin with because if
you didn't have that you would not have
even abstained from masturbation and
sexuality and so on but now the next
step is you realize okay now I can't and
get the rid of all of this
I need to actually train my mind in
regard to it so my mind is not moved by
it because again itch comes from the
body being there being vital being alive
being hormonal being whatever
but how that internal itch of your body
affects your mind that's the that's on
you whether your mind is moved by it and
whether your mind is moved by it and
projected to essential desires and ideas
or completely indifferent seeing the
danger of sensual desires and ideas and
not going there then that itch is not an
itch it's just an aspect of this body
and how it's felt
that's what it would have said for as
long as a man is not developed
internally in regard to his own body
he's not going to overcome the desire
towards the the external counterparts of
his sexuality so you need to be your own
mind needs to be developed in regard to
your own body and that's what means your
your own sexual itch
and by being developed means unmoved
ceasing to expect the scratch and
ceasing to expect the itch to go away
because see
the only experience of absent each that
you know is the experience of after
aftermath of scratching
and that's not actually absence of a
niche that's just numbing the itch that's
that's just numbing the itch that's
still there
numbing the wound that still hurts
so that's what that's why it's it's it's
a problem to want the H to go away with
a version and act out of it because any
knowledge of each note being there is
the knowledge of each still being there
just numbed on account of my central
Endeavors and scratching
so if you abstain from both scratching
it and wishing it to to get rid of it
you will actually get to learn truly
what freedom from an H is
you know like I said it's like the
immediate calming of that itch yes it will
calming of that itch yes it will
eventually become immediate coming we're
just seeing right through it removes it
and then you wouldn't even have to see
right through it itch will cease to
signify the scratch which means it won't
be an itch anymore